unfcu.org 2002-12-03

# UNFCU Privacy Policy

|   
---  

**We Care about Your Privacy**

At UNFCU, we are committed to safeguarding your financial information and maintaining your privacy. To help you understand how UNFCU collects, uses and protects your personal information, we have established policies and procedures, which are detailed here in the UNFCU Privacy Policy.   
Please take the time to read this policy; it contains information on both member privacy and Internet privacy . If you have any questions, please email us at[ email@unfcu.com](mailto:email@unfcu.com). 

**Privacy Policy**

**Member Privacy**  
Over the years UNFCU has worked hard to earn your trust and we will continue to be vigilant in maintaining the privacy of our members. To that end, we have instituted policies and procedures intended to ensure that your personal information is handled safely and responsibly. As you will see in the statement of our privacy practices, we take this responsibility very seriously and are committed to providing you with the highest level of member service and confidentiality.

It is our promise that UNFCU will collect only the information necessary to deliver to you quality products and services. Furthermore, we are continually assessing new technology as it becomes available in order to continue to best protect your privacy.

**(A) What information do we collect and what may we disclose?**  
UNFCU collects, uses and retains information about you only for specific business purposes where it is necessary in administering our business for you and in providing competitive products, services, and other opportunities that will satisfy your financial service needs. 

We collect the following "nonpublic personal information" about you from the following sources: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms, such as your name, address, social security numbers, assets, and income;  

  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others, such as the account balance, payment history, and parties to transactions; and  

  * Information we receive from a consumer-reporting agency, such as your creditworthiness and credit history.

At times, it becomes necessary to provide to third parties nonpublic personal information about you that we collect in order to facilitate transaction processing. Examples of these third parties would include title insurance companies, statement production vendors, collection agencies, credit card service bureaus, and cheque service providers who provide support or services for one or more of our products. In addition, UNFCU may provide nonpublic personal information about you to specially selected third parties who offer enhanced products and services such as GlobalPhone, Incorporated. All these third parties have been carefully chosen by UNFCU and agree to safeguard your confidential information with the same commitment to privacy as we have.

**(B) What happens if my information is incorrect or incomplete?**  
We have implemented procedures to help ensure that member financial information is maintained in a manner that will ensure it is accurate, current and complete. If you have reason to believe that your information is incomplete or inaccurate, we invite you to contact us so we can correct our records promptly.

**(C) Who has access to my information?**  
For your protection, UNFCU staff is required to verify the identity of the individual or member who is requesting the account information. Only you and verified joint accountholders are entitled to obtain information about your account. We thank you for your assistance in cooperating with our identification procedures when you contact us.

We limit staff access to confidential member information only to those employees with a business reason for knowing such information. UNFCU educates its staff so that they understand the importance UNFCU places on confidentiality and member privacy. In addition, we maintain security standards and procedures to help prevent unauthorized access to confidential information about you. Member privacy is also addressed in our Employee Handbook, and any staff that violates this policy will be subject to appropriate disciplinary measures.

We do not reveal specific information about your accounts or other personally identifiable data to unaffiliated third parties for their independent use, unless:

  1. You request or authorize it; 
  2. The information is provided to help complete a transaction initiated by you;
  3. The information is provided to a credit bureau or similar information reporting agency;
  4. The disclosure is otherwise permitted or required by law.

**(D) How does UNFCU protect my information from unauthorized access?**  
UNFCU maintains and follows strict security standards and procedures designed to guard against unauthorized access to and disclosure of confidential member information. Whenever reasonably possible, we will use security-coding techniques to protect against unauthorized access to your personal records, ensure accuracy and integrity of communications and transactions, and protect your confidentiality.

**(E) Are there any exceptions that I should know about?**  
Under certain circumstances, your member information may be shared with our wholly owned subsidiary, the Investment Centre at UNFCU, in order to market additional products and services, and to ensure we consider your entire relationship with us when making decisions about the products and services we provide to you.

We may also share information with the Investment Centre in order to provide services necessary to maintain your accounts. Examples of such information may include information about your identity, your transaction history with UNFCU, your current financial condition, and information obtained from a credit report or other sources outside of our institution.

**(F) How can I avoid having my information shared with nonaffiliated parties?**  
If you prefer that we not disclose nonpublic personal information about you to an affiliated or nonaffiliated third party, you may opt out of those disclosures; that is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures (other than disclosures permitted by law). If you wish to opt out of nonaffiliated third-party mailings, simply click here. 

Please be assured that UNFCU will not directly, or through the Investment Centre, disclose any nonpublic personal information about you to a nonaffiliated third party unless all of these conditions are fulfilled:

  1. UNFCU has provided you with an initial notice of its Privacy Policy;
  2. UNFCU has provided you an opt-out notice;
  3. And UNFCU has given you an opportunity, before the information is disclosed, to opt out of this disclosure.

However, please be aware that your right to opt out will not apply to disclosures that are legally permitted or to disclosures we make to companies that perform services on our behalf. Situations where this type of sharing could take place could include:

  1. When UNFCU contracts with third parties to help deliver our services to you, i.e. property appraisal firm, credit card processing;
  2. When credit bureaus or others, and only when appropriate, ask for credit references. UNFCU will not share your account number, password, or Personal Identification Numbers (PINs) with nonaffiliated third parties for purposes of their marketing to you;
  3. In the instance of a sale or merger of part or all of our business.

When we share information with third parties, we hold all such parties to the same high standards as we do ourselves with respect to the privacy of your information.

**Internet Privacy**   
When you visit our website at www.unfcu.org, we want you to feel secure that we are respecting your privacy. The majority of online forms on the UNFCU website are protected with 128 bit SSL encryption. This encryption protects the user's information from being viewed by an unauthorized party.

We protect your account information by placing it on the secure portion of our website. That's why you have to enter a unique member number and password each time you want to access your account information. In addition, you can use the sign off button located throughout the Internet Account Access portion of the website to securely exit your account without closing your browser. Your password should never be shared with anyone.

**(A) General Website Pages**  
When you browse through www.unfcu.org and have not registered for any online service from UNFCU, you browse anonymously. Personal information -- such as your name, address, phone number or email address \-- is not collected as you browse.

UNFCU does, however, collect and store information, or "cookies," on the domain you use to access our website, the Internet address of the site from which you linked directly to its site, and the date and time of your visit to our website. This information is used to measure the number of visitors to the various pages on the UNFCU website, to help us make improvements to the information contained on the site, and to better serve our members through special marketing and service programmes.

**(B) Restricted Account Access Website Pages**  
Personal identifying information is collected when a member registers to access his/her UNFCU account(s) via the Internet. This information enables UNFCU to regulate entry to the restricted portions of its website and to measure member usage. Any personal identifying information gathered during member registrations is not sold to third parties.

**(C) Third Parties**  
UNFCU will make full disclosure online when information is being collected for transference to or usage by other parties. Please note that by accessing the noted link, which will appear on the UNFCU webpage when you leave the UNFCU website to enter a website hosted by another party, you will no longer be subject to, or under the protection of, the privacy and security policies of our website. We encourage you to read and evaluate the privacy and security policies on the site you are entering, which may be different than ours.

**(D) Personal Information**  
Personal information contained in email sent by members and non-members may be used by UNFCU staff and volunteers to answer questions, to follow up on suggestions or complaints, or to improve the level of service UNFCU provides.

We may use information you have given us to, for example, provide a service, ensure proper billing, measure consumer interest in our various services, and inform you about products and services.

When we send emails to you, we may be able to identify information about your email address, such as whether you can read graphic-rich html emails. If your email address is html-enabled, we may choose to send you graphic-rich html emails.

Please note that we do not provide your email address to our business partners. However, we may send you offers on behalf of our business partners. Keep in mind that if you take advantage of an offer from a UNFCU business partner and become their customer, they may independently wish to send offers to you. In this case, you will need to inform them separately if you wish to decline receiving future offers from them.

**(E) Warning Concerning Email**  
Please be advised that email messages sent to us from outside of our specified web forms may not be secure against interception by unauthorized individuals. Therefore, if you wish to communicate sensitive or personal information, you may want to send it by postal mail. UNFCU will not share email addresses with outside parties.

**(F) Opt Out Internet Policy**  
Any member who does not wish to receive email promotions or notices can reply to any email sent and ask to be removed from the UNFCU email list. 

We want you to understand our commitment to privacy issues and our use of confidential member information. If you are concerned about your financial privacy and want to know more about this important subject, or if you have a question regarding this Privacy Policy, please call us at (212) 338-8100 or send an email to[ email@unfcu.com](mailto:email@unfcu.com). You can also write us at the following address:

> United Nations Federal Credit Union  
>  820 Second Avenue, 12th Floor  
>  New York, NY 10017-4504, USA  
>  ATTN: Member Directed Services 

These privacy principles apply to all UNFCU members, all former members and all nonmember consumers.
